PAWAN PRASAD

Home No.5, Street No.2

Jai Bharat Enclave, Mohan Nagar

Ghaziabad, U.P-201007 Mobile: +91- 7503185969

Mail id: pawanprasad1993@gmail.com Website: http://www.pawanprasad.com/

SUMMARY

Having 3 years of total IT experience in BI also worked on the projects related to computer vision (OpenCV), Predictive modeling and natural language processing by using python as a language tool. Having the knowledge about python libraries like pandas, openCV, NLTK, sklearn, scipy, numpy. Having introductory knowledge about SAS.

EXPERIENCE

Senior Analyst, Sopra Steria

Noida, Jan 2017 – present

Working as BI developer for client Deutsche Bank Germany, also involve in Machine learning and Data Science related POCs and project within the organization.

Project: Deutsche Bank, Germany (March 2018 - current)

Working as BI developer on disturbed agile model in CTB team.

- Develop ETL mapping for data integration from Database, CRM web services.
- Writing complex SQL queries for data analysis.
- Developed various python script to automate various task.
- Using query studios in cognos for providing testing support.
- Created python script to load database configuration table from excel sheet for GDPR.

Python and Machine learning Projects

Project 1 : Face recognition using openCV (Feb 2018– March 2018)

Created a working prototype of face recognition using python to implement faceId based folder locker for a banking client using Haar Cascade and LBPHFaceRecognizer.

Project 2: Machine Learning based auto ticket assignment(March 2017-current)

A machine learning based application that auto assign the ticket to developers based on ticket history.

- For feasibility analysis created training dataset by using a python crawler to get incident data from bugs.eclipse.org
- Developed python script for data cleaning and data provisioning
- Visualize data using python libraries.
- Used multi-class classification models form sklearn python libraries
- Developed python script to automate the testing data accuracy result.

Software Engineer, LexisNexis

Gurgaon, Nov 2016 - Jan 2017

Project: Content Conversion Processing Team (Nov 2016 – Jan 2017)

The role required in the project to implement different stages of ETL and conversion process

with Informatica mapping, Java and Perl scripts.

- Creating ETL application to fetch the data from different sources and send the converted data into centralized Data warehouse to deliver the content online.
- Writing SQL queries to validate ETL jobs.
- Developed python crawlers to fetch data from webpage and populate into DB.
- Used python to automate task various task in python.

Project: Edison Lab - Identification of metadata form cases text data

LexisNexis have judiciary decision legal data which have metadata like judge name, parties involved, in-favour decision. This metadata used to be tag manually by some person which reads the whole text and identify the metadata, usually this is done by third party.

We trained a machine learning model which can predict the Judge Name, Parties, Party which won the case. My role and responsibilities was:-

- Creating training and testing dataset from PDFs and XMLs
- Performing data cleaning on test and training data.
- Performing feature engineering like stemming and Lemmatization using NLTK.
- Used named entity recognition to find metadata using NLTK.
- Using sklearn libraries to extract features and normalization.
- Using sklearn inbuilt model for classification.

Programmer Analyst, Cognizant Technology Solution

Kolkata, West Bengal— JUN, 2015 - NOV, 2016

Worked as ETL (Informatica) and Data Warehouse developer in insurance domain for the client METLIFE. My role and responsibilities was:-

- Understand the ETL specifications and build the ETL applications like Mappings.
- Writing complex SQL for data analysis.
- Writing UNIX script for batch job execution and to implement ETL execution logic.
- Attend various web sessions on SAS.

EDUCATION

2014	B. Tech (Electronics and Communication) H.R Institute of Technology, UPTU 70.1%
2010	AISSCE, Swami Vivekanad Sarswati Vidhay Mandir, Ghaziabad, CBSE, 74%
2008	AISSE, Swami Vivekanad Sarswati Vidhay Mandir, Ghaziabad, 78%

SKILLS

- Data Engineer Skills: ETL (Informatica Power Center), SQL, Data warehousing, RDBMS
- **Programming Languages**: Python 3.x, Java, UNIX Shell Scripting.
- **Python Libraries:** numpy, pandas, scipy, NLTK, sklearn